<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Wmdoqcocg</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Wmdoqcocg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 14:33:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/71966692-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 14:33:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/71966692-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>Sooner or later, many will ask: What does Jesus teach us about the end-times, the Second Coming and related prophetic events? To answer this question, let us follow the roadmap laid out by Jesus in His parables and discourses with an open Bible. We’ll discover that while we cannot pin down specific dates, we can understand the principles, signs and sequence of world-changing events. The more accurately we align our lives to those teachings, the less these events will “catch” us unawares.</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/46424479-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 14:01:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/46424479-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>After spending more than 20 years providing church consultations, I've seen a number of things work and a number of things fail. I'd like to take the risk today to highlight one key reason why some consultations do not succeed. It is my sincere hope that this will enable better processes in the future and lead churches toward greater health and alignment with God's call for their lives.
Before you read further, allow me to be clear: the following comments do not apply to every consultation nor to all who provide these services.</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/23341845-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 13:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/23341845-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>In contemporary conversations about Christianity, the concept of hell often triggers a variety of responses. Some find the idea of eternal punishment to be barbaric. Others embrace it as a necessary divine response to sin. But if we consider how Christianity speaks of both heaven and hell, an important difference emerges when discussing their respective emphases: Christians appear to convey more fear-based teachings regarding hell rather than emphasizing the simple absence from God's presence, which is commonly perceived as the biblical implication for those not making it into "</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/48378035-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 23:42:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/48378035-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>As Christians, we are called to love, forgive, and be kind to one another. However, it’s often remarked upon (even by ourselves) that we can fall short in these endeavors. While there may never be an end to the human capacity for growth, there is something about our sinful natures and self-righteous hearts that can sabotage even the best of intentions when it comes to being kind. There are a few key reasons as to why we can be particularly unskillful in this department, and, with proper recognition of the issues, we can work towards rectifying them.</description></item><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/16802092-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 19:38:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/16802092-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>In an era of increased threats to freedom, pluralism and secular democracies across the globe, it is incumbent upon the church and religious institutions to fost er a democratic spirit that takes responsibility for its own liberties and freedoms. This paper underscores the importance of a conceptual shift from a defensive stance which tends to ring alarm bells only when there are clear infringements on religious rights, towards a proactive one where the church commits itself to nurturing a healthy and inclusive public sphere for all faiths and none.</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/63232147-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 18:19:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/63232147-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>As a Christian, we're called to treat fellow believers like family. That’s one of the ways we build a strong and cohesive spiritual community. However, sometimes we struggle with this ideal. We may have tensions or conflicts with other church members or just feel less connected than we should. It doesn't mean you've failed or your faith is waning, but it could be time for some introspection and reevaluation of your practices.</description></item><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/80098415-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 22:38:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/80098415-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>In today’s society, a lot is discussed regarding different perspectives of religion. Among many, Christian fundamentalism has attracted significant focus due to the unique tenets it holds. As with any other viewpoint, understanding the good and the bad of Christian fundamentalism calls for delving into both its positive aspects as well as potential dangers. For this purpose, we will analyze core principles and real-life manifestations of this ideology.
The Good of Christian Fundamentalism Strong Beliefs: Christian fundamentalists hold to orthodox doctrines of their faith.</description></item><item><title>9 Lessons for New Christians ... And Old Ones</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/38926561-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 12:02:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/38926561-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</guid><description>In all of our lives, we’ve likely heard about the existence or truth of God through conversations or experiences. For some of us, that process may have been gradual or relatively simple. For others, it was quite challenging and difficult to comprehend. Yet no matter what our initial path to faith has looked like, becoming a Christian is an active step of surrender and commitment. It marks the beginning of a lifelong journey in which we deepen our understanding of who God is and walk closely with him.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/58659596-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 17:32:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/58659596-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>In our highly advanced society, technology continues to develop and affect every corner of life. While there are many benefits that come with technological progress, it also raises interesting questions about how Christians should approach this phenomenon. Is new technology always a good thing or can it pose negative consequences as well? How do we find the right balance between embracing new innovations but guarding against potential dangers? Here, we'll explore the answers to these important questions through a Christian perspective on advances in technology.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/79227336-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 02:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/79227336-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>One of the most important things I’ve come to learn, especially in my role as a Ministry Director overseeing the care for pastors, is that many leaders struggle with asking others for help. There are numerous reasons, including pride and fear, but all in all, it boils down to a lack of well-practiced skill or paradigm shift. So, how do we help our brothers and sisters get past this reality? It begins with understanding.</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/13777359-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 22:42:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/13777359-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>A proliferation of ideas about heaven has evolved over the centuries. Few of these notions come from a careful study of Scripture, yet they persistently manifest in movies, music, art and popular culture. Christians must be vigilant not to allow others' imaginings to influence their understanding of what God has revealed in the Bible. After all, the Lord promised:
“Heaven and earth will pass away, but My words will by no means pass away” (Matthew 24:35).</description></item><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/58892984-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 17:08:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/58892984-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>Everyone goes through the valley of despair at one time or another. While this quote comes from an 1845 romantic novel, The Two Daughters by William Harrison Ainsworth, it’s a timeless adage we can all identify with. Circumstances in life can create a downward spiral where we find ourselves feeling overwhelmed and uncertain about the future.
For a believer struggling with doubt, disillusionment, or despair, building trust back into a relationship with God is the challenge at hand.</description></item><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/71082381-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 16:11:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/71082381-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>According to numerous research and surveys, we are in a period of what is often called "the great disestablishment." The percentage of people who claim no religion has risen considerably. In a Pew survey conducted in 34 different countries during 2012-2014, they found that for the first time in human history one fifth of the world’s population is religiously unaffiliated (Pew Research Center, October 1, 2015). There have been similar reports from other respected institutions such as the Barna Group and PIPO Research (2017).</description></item><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/18617734-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 21:53:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/18617734-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>Throughout Christian history, there have been many important groups that have emphasized love and care for those in need. In the early Church, this was especially evident through the deacon system, whereby men were entrusted with meeting physical needs of members as well as others within the community, particularly widows and orphans. While the role of deacons has evolved over time, the biblical mandate to provide for the poor and vulnerable remains a deeply rooted part of Christianity today.</description></item><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/92909826-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 17:12:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/92909826-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>There is a fine line that we must walk on in order to take care of ourselves, without treading into the realm of self-centeredness and neglecting others. This article will explore the often misunderstood and misconstrued concept of self-care and offer suggestions for achieving a healthy balance in our lives. While God commands us to love our neighbors as ourselves and to have care and compassion for others (Mark 12:30; Galatians 6:2), He also created us with real needs.</description></item><item><title>Guilt and the Great Deception in the Christian Life</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/56878891-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:29:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/56878891-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</guid><description>A lingering sense of guilt can plague a Christian's heart, causing doubt, despair, and even rebellion against God. This is no light matter and needs to be addressed for true spiritual health and growth. This article will examine how guilt can creep in, often due to misunderstanding the great biblical paradigms of God's grace and our freedom in Christ. We will then work through some solutions, grounded in truth from Scripture, that help to restore our joyful trust in the Savior.</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/48016175-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 03:45:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wmdoqcocg.github.io/posts/48016175-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>As believers, we've received the wonderful gift of eternal life through Jesus Christ (John 3:16). This doesn't mean that once saved, we are automatically living the most fulfilling lives. Our Christian walk is a lifelong process of growth, learning, and choosing how to live our lives in honor of God (2 Corinthians 3:18). One way to examine whether or not we're building our lives on biblical foundations, is to evaluate what we base our worth and identity upon.</description></item></channel></rss>